foreign
[Music]
hello welcome to the round table this is
Round Table number 21 and I'm your host
Gonzalo Lira and today is uh Tuesday
September 20th 2022 and we're going to
have a very interesting discussion I
have three wonderful guests and I'll
introduce them to you in turn Ray
McGovern is a former CIA officer Ray
how's it going good to see you my friend
doing well thank you oh it's a pleasure
having you on again uh I have John
kiriaku the famous CIA whistleblower
John a pleasure to meet you the pleasure
is all mine Gonzalo thanks so much for
the invitation oh thank you very much
for accepting it's a real pleasure a
real delight and Susie Dawson uh a
activist on the intelligence front Susie
nice to meet you nice to meet you sir
Gonzalez thank you so much for coming on
and uh the thing that the the reason I
wanted to have you on is the listeners
know that uh I was away for almost two
weeks because my YouTube channel got uh
suspended got a strike because I talked
about the malady that shall not be named
so you all three are warmed we cannot
mention the malady or much less the
medication that's been used for it but
talking about that forthrightly is no
longer possible and what I found
fascinating is all these Revelations
whereby the US government is working
with these private platforms to
essentially censor information now I
actually lived in the Peniche
dictatorship I always bring this up that
in the penetrative chairship there was
less repression and more free speech in
the west than there in in Chile back in
the day than there is in the west today
and I'm I wanted to the the thing that I
I find fascinating is how the government
has outsourced repressive technology
measures and I want to get your uh
opinion John because you're you're like
you were one of the first whistleblowers
that started talking about the excesses
of the uh American intelligence
community and I want to get your opinion
about what you think of how the US
government is outsourcing repression uh
what do you think of all this oh yeah
well you know it's a it's a very
appropriate uh question because today is
the 75th anniversary of the creation of
the CIA uh I didn't know that yeah
yeah that's kind of funny yeah
we I've been thinking about this a lot
lately because uh there have been calls
uh from some important people people who
might have a great deal of respect for
uh to create a new church committee or
something akin to a new church committee
uh you know the church committee did
wonderful historic amazing work and
exposing crimes that the CIA and the FBI
were committing against Americans and
against uh uh foreign Nationals well
post 911 and and don't forget that 21
years have already passed since 9 11. uh
the the reforms that the church
committee enacted
have really just Fallen by the wayside
uh we've got a CIA now that has an
active assassination program a CIA that
won't even acknowledge that there is
such a thing as a drone program a CIA
that had a a secret prison system around
the world a CIA that carries out
International kidnappings that they
euphemistically call Renditions
there are there are so many things that
the CIA is doing in in the name of the
American people
for which there is no oversight or very
little oversight that it's essentially
undone all of the good things that the
church committee had accomplished the
FBI is is just as bad NSA is just as bad
you know it's a part of the nsa's
charter
that it's not permitted to collect
information on American citizens or U.S
persons that's any anybody here on a on
a green card
um and in fact that's almost exclusively
what they do uh we haven't even begun
talking about DARPA and about uh the the
Myriad of of contractors and uh defense
and intelligence related uh consulting
firms around the Beltway here in
Washington you know Gonzalo it's not an
accident that there are now more
millionaires per capita in the
Washington DC area than anywhere else in
America including Silicon Valley
it's not an accident yeah I know got
very rich
911 and its aftermath but what I find
what I find incredible is is how so many
of the repressive measures that are
being implemented by the American
government are being subcontracted out
so that there there's absolutely
reliability
absolutely I mean look at look at well
they call them butts in the seats that
that's the that's what they call them at
the CIA there are people who don't
really work for the CIA they work for
Booz Allen Hamilton or they work for
saic or happy or any any one of a number
of uh of outfits uh and they have a bud
in a seat and they they punch in
information in a computer or they you
know run some clandestine program
um the CIA doesn't have to pay for their
health insurance or their pension
contribution and uh and then everybody's
happy but then at the same time even
while everybody's happy there's no
accountability there's nobody that that
has to answer to anyone again you know
one of the great things that came out of
the church committee was the creation of
the Senate select committee on
intelligence and the house permanent
select committee on intelligence
oversight committees for the
intelligence Community well they're just
cheerleading organizations yeah oversee
anything
yeah you know I saw a video of yours
Susie that that how you discussed the um
the the the the motivation of these
intelligence firms since there there are
for profit corporations they want to be
increasing their revenue and so
basically they start targeting everybody
yeah well that's the problem when you
subcontract
um the targeting of citizens to
for-profit agencies in order for them to
make more profit they need to Target
more people and I think I I mentioned
and I think I know the film that you're
talking about and I mentioned in there
how when security cameras first came
into residential areas or commercial
districts you know you had like one
camera and then another kilometer One
camera and then it was like 800 meters
and it was 600 meters and now you have
four cameras on the same wall of the
same shop and um it's just this cycle
where to make more money they're
actually Target more people
um
did you hear about how there's an AI
that if you take a picture on Instagram
this AI can look at the picture and
figure out which cameras were filming
you while you took the picture and and
and show them to you and this is a
commercially available product that is
for people people's Amusement so in
terms of intelligence you can imagine
how much you're being surveilled yeah
absolutely and studying NSA documents
from Snowden Falls you say the same
thing they talk about wanting to be able
to geolocate to the meter anywhere on
the planet no matter which country it's
in they do it from space the national
geospatial agency later in our uh as
well in this area National surveillance
officers that I think Ray would know
there's a whole bunch of these agencies
that are aside from the CIA and NSA
which are part of this ecosystem of
spying and their agencies that in some
cases have more Personnel than NSA or
CIA but which nobody ever even cares
about but they're end game and they
admit it in their own documents that the
end game is to create a control grid of
the entire planet it's it's in black and
white in their own documents it's
basically a panopticon a panopticon
prison where where the warden can see
every single prisoner and and nobody can
make a move with without any any kind of
Freedom Ray let me ask you to bring you
into the conversation you know how do we
solve this what would be the Practical
steps necessary in order to change this
around and have an intelligence service
that does its job but serves the people
and doesn't try to in essence it seems
to me kind of like enslave the people
well Gonzalo I I uh compliment you on
your Greek derivative
panopticon yeah it literally means see
everything you know
uh and that's pretty much as Susie has
already indicated the name of the game
now I'd like to go back to what uh John
kiriapo said uh he's an expert on
torture having refused to be trained in
the techniques of enhanced interrogation
techniques
and having blown the whistle on it now
it's very courageous thing to do uh it
ended it ended up with him having to
spend two years in prison
I visited John in prison I saw all kinds
of folks were there with John and how I
was so glad that John could defend
himself
uh that's neither here nor there let's
talk about the so-called
oversight committees right well long
since they have become
Overlook committees you know the
overlooked Committees of the Senate and
the house now just yesterday
a federal judge or district judge a
ruled that we are not allowed to see the
extensive
6700 page
Senate intelligence committee research
document on CIA
torture based on CIA
documents okay
now
people need to be reminded how this
evolved
uh it took five years to do it started
out when
when under the order of Gina haspel the
chief CIA person in the first CIA black
site in Thailand waterboarding and worse
we're done okay she was there she
watched it she wasn't right there she
rushed it through the proverbial window
make sure as you know what she wanted
okay now
the tapes that were made were destroyed
by whom oh bite you to Asheville and her
boss now even a Republican senator was
outraged at then we have to
creation
later the Republicans bowed out of the
investigation but what came out of that
was a really gutsy report shepherded by
Dianne Feinstein who unfortunately is
now in her dotage but in those days
uncharacteristically
I think because she stood up for these
people that she saw working night and
day to get to the bottom of this and who
came by quite quite felicitously
serious
bear
original studies done at the behest of
the then CIA director Leon Panetta I
mean they had all the goods right there
okay now what happened
they started drafting this thing and
President Obama was opposed to it he had
his chief of staff attend all of these
meetings that were sensibly designed to
to redact it to to sanitize it okay
every one of those meetings what did
this person do I think it was McCullough
is that his name anyhow uh he was there
to make sure that the CI interests were
protected why because John Brennan and
Barack Obama uh had this twin
relationship where Barack Obama was
going to do everything he possibly could
to defend John Brennan
now when it came out that John Brennan
sent his folks into the Senate
intelligence committee computers
Dianne Feinstein got a little girl got a
little upset at that okay
suffice it to say that she oversaw a
document of 6700 pages but
reduced to 525 page redacted executive
summary now the summary is enough to
indict everyone involved the summary is
awful you you have to the the summary
yeah just the summary I mean it's
redacted but you learn that
these these terrible techniques and
they're named were not effective they
didn't produce any valid information
that the CIA lied about it to the
president and to everyone else that oh
yeah we're getting good information on
tourism and anything and that the
techniques themselves were followers
than any briefed to the White House or
to anybody else okay those were the main
conclusions and gory detail is included
now what happened
it's the end of Dianne Feinstein's term
as head of the Senate select committee
on intelligence what's she gonna do is
she going to go ahead and publish this
redacted summary or is she going to Bow
like most people and do Overlook rather
than oversight
I don't know what accounted for her
courage I think it was her loyalty to
these folks who worked so hard for her
okay who did so much and came up with
this redacted versions which spoke
volumes in and of themselves but she was
also helped by a senator named Udall
Udall lost this re-election capability
and you had all said you know if you
don't release that terrible document I'm
gonna release it from the floor of
Congress
whoa that that allowed or propelled even
Obama to say okay we redacted the 525
page summary so all right let it go out
there and we just will tell the Press
don't play it up it's just you know
we're trying to catch terrorists right
okay yeah so that so it's published in
December of
2014 I think okay so what happens
um it's pretty much kept the wraps on uh
and when Richard Burr I live in North
Carolina now uh he's still one of our
Senators when he became chair of the
Senate intelligence committee replacing
Dianne Feinstein he said those are
congressional documents I want them all
back here I'm going to take care of them
every one of you executive agencies give
me those documents
and they did now I S I suspect that
there may have been one kept at the CIA
but I also suspect that cheetah haspel
destroyed that before she left office as
get this director of the CIA what's the
morale what's the moral of this story
well uh not only are the Senate and
House intelligence committees
feckless
and unable to do what the uh what the
commission asked them to do very early
on uh but they're actually facilitate
the hiding of these things and I dare
say they know that the CI the FBI have
as much on them as as would be very
embarrassing or they just step out of
line and do the right thing lastly
Richard Burr was caught
selling stock when code when he got a
briefing on Covert and he he just you
know really just did what he could to
enhance his profits that's well known
he's going out of out of office in
January and the sooner the better but
you know it's not only he I'll just add
one more thing
the Senate
Judiciary Committee
headed by a super annuated guy from Iowa
whose name will occur to me in a second
John kiriako you probably will Grassley
Congress okay all right so here what
happens with respect to Watergate is
this lawyer kleinsmith is discovered to
have falsified documents to justify a
fisa request okay kleinsmann okay what
does he get well his wife is pregnant
and so he gets no jail time okay for
deliberately falsifying this document
okay that's a felony okay so what
happens restly comments in a in a we
call it
a tweet okay a grassly queen and he says
oh so this this shows that the justice
department has no power over these over
these people uh what happens is uh it's
the department of just us is what Wesley
says and no one will ever go to no one
ever go to jail they take care of
themselves now why is the significant
regressively is the chairman of the them
or almost chairman now he has been
chairman he'll be chairman again
probably of the Senate uh Judiciary
Committee he's 91 years old I think
that's even older than I am I think he's
even less accomplishmentous than I am
sorry to carry on so long that's all
right that's all right it's it's
delightful to hear you uh but you know
one of the things I notice and uh John
helped me out here because it seems to
me that the uh Obama administration
oddly enough the Democrat Administration
that's all for civil liberties and you
know free speech and all the rest of it
it seemed to be more obsessed with
intelligence and cracking down on
intelligence
I had friends at the White House at the
time who described Barack Obama's
obsession with leaks as nicksonian it
was a nicksonian obsession with National
Security leaks and I was told also at
the time that this was because of John
Brennan remember Obama tried to name
Brennan as CIA director uh in
2009 at the beginning of his first term
and progressives just threw a fit and so
so Obama the thing is I just want to be
clear I'm I'm politically conservative
and very conservative that and I think
that John Brennan is just you know he is
he looks like a shyster you know drug
dealer almost I mean I would trust him
as far as I could throw him to tell you
the truth so I understand the
progressives exactly you know there's
there's actually a great story to the
career of John Brennan I I worked for
John Brennan when I was still on the
analytics side at the CIA uh John was a
gs-15 uh Deputy Chief of the Arab
Israeli group in the office of near
Eastern South Asian analysis okay he was
a mid-level functionary like so many of
us were
and um he worked for a woman named
Martha Kessler who was like the U.S
government's leading expert on Syria
Martha wrote a book called Syria fragile
Mosaic of power that we all had to read
when we went oh god oh oh so she could
get you know pick up some royalties
right
he worked for her but she didn't like
him and finally he went to her this was
in this was in like
1996 I'm gonna say and
um 1995. and uh he said look I've worked
for you for a long time I think I'm
ready for promotion into the senior
intelligence service and she said that
not only will you never be in the senior
intelligence service I don't even want
you working for me anymore you're fired
and at the agency when you're fired
fired you're not really fired you have
six weeks to to walk the halls and find
another job and if you do you're good
and if you don't then you're fired six
weeks within within the agency itself
within the agency exactly well it's
Christmas time and you know the normal
turnover for jobs is in the summer so
John goes out there and he starts
looking for a job he ends up going to
the pdb staff the president's Daily
Brief where where Ray was uh was a star
and because it was off cycle
uh they were able to offer him a job as
a briefer for the lowest ranking person
entitled to a pdb briefing that was the
director of intelligence programs at the
National Security Council who at the
time happened to be one George Tennant
so yeah they immediately hit it off
because they were exactly alike their
mean aggressive alpha dogs cigar smoking
you know just two awful people hit it up
George was promoted to Deputy uh
director of the CIA and he brings uh uh
John Brennan back with him and what does
he do he makes John Brennan deputy
director of The Office of near Eastern
and South Asian analysis Martha
Kessler's boss
so John calls Martha oh his office oh
now you're fired
okay I mean I gotta admit as a story
it's pretty good and and pretty sweet
for Brennan I mean let's give the devil
his due
can you give us background on John
Brennan because
you don't want to I I absolutely no I
think it's important to actually because
there's a trail of dead bodies behind
John Brennan not many people talk about
and I don't actually just mean
um those that you would assume in the
war on terror
um but I mean actually on Western soil
and particularly journalists and Brennan
was the attack dog of Obama that is true
but Brennan absolutely relished the role
and Brennan had very personal beefs with
Julie massage and with Wikileaks but
also with someone else who almost never
gets talked about in fact has almost
been disappeared from the discourse
that's an extremely Brave Rolling Stone
reporter called Michael Hastings Michael
Hastings was going on CNN and MSNBC and
major mainstream platforms and he was
completely eviscerating the Obama
Administration the war on terror
particularly the military U.S military
effort in Afghanistan he wrote an
extremely famous expose on it was
General Stanley mcquisto am I right Ray
yes right who ended up getting fired by
Obama on the basis of the reporting of
Michael Hastings while Michael Hastings
was also the first famous or earliest
famous reporter outside of Glenn and
Glenn Greenwood and Laura poitrus um to
openly support Snowden and when I say
support Snowden I mean in the minutes
after Snowden coming out when before he
had even left Hong Kong when everybody
was waking up every day expecting that
they would see the news that Snowden had
been captured or killed Michael Hastings
go and look at his Twitter timeline at
MM Hastings and see the tweets I'm
talking about more than 50 of his tweets
on his timeline were advocating for
Snowden and far and wide and that was at
a time where it was extremely dangerous
to support Snowden in those first
minutes and hours and days after the
first known disclosures Michael Hastings
was also working on his next big story
at that time and his next big story was
an expose on Ron Brennan then director
of the CIA
likely in the context of Brennan's
targeting of Julian Assange and
Wikileaks who Hastings had also been
outspoken and supportive Hastings had
met with Julian several times Hastings
had written a series of articles about
Julian and Wikileaks
um so Hastings was on the proverbial
[__] list I don't know what else to call
it for a number of reasons but having
taken down a general having supported
Wikileaks and Julian throughout the
smear campaigns and the the D
platforming and the attacks that
Wikileaks was facing in that period of
2009 through 2013 then openly advocating
for snow and then the final straw
endearing to investigate the director of
the CIA John Brennan and who expose him
for his own mentality Michael Hastings
then reported uh that he believed his
cut his vehicle was being tampered with
he borrowed a neighbor's car he reached
out to Jen Robinson Wikileaks lawyer and
shared his fears that he was being
targeted by the FBI and his
his car his late model BMW borrowed from
the neighbor in fact
exploded into some of the Reigns on a
Los Angeles Boulevard
um less than 48 hours after he first
started complaining to those around him
that he was in fear and he was being
severely targeted by U.S intelligence
agencies that is a U.S citizen on U.S
soil
um exercising their first amendment
rights exercising their political
freedoms doing so to enormous audiences
and with the motivation of protection of
Truth tell us and um you know be it
Julian beard Snowden bit whoever and
um we needed that voice and we needed
that voice
no we need that voice now we've needed
it ever since 2013. that voice was
silence and the there was to be an
investigation it was swiftly covered up
everything was smoothed over and now
nobody speaks the name Michael Hastings
so
um in respects to Michael and the work
that he did I wanted to tell that story
now and also there was something else
that made me think of it and that's
John's sacrifice because John right here
is why the world knows about CIA torture
John is why Obama had to address it John
is why there was a report and that we
have the information that we do have and
John has paid a deep price for that as
well so I just want to show respect to
you too John you're amazing
yeah
go ahead go ahead you don't have to ask
permission no
well you know I'm a Catholic and I
always ask for permission
um
I'm a lapsed Catholic I have found it
it's easier to ask for forgiveness than
permission
[Laughter]
with respect to Hastings thanks so much
Susie for bringing that into a wider
view
um what happened to uh Hastings I can be
readily explained by something that
Julian Assange himself
revealed and that is a so-called set of
offensive cyber War tactics
that came out of this Bevy of things
that were released what was they a
minute uh Vault 17 yeah
yeah okay now just to remind folks uh
there were all kinds of really fancy
techniques that the CIA had had
devised and implemented one of them was
you could be asleep in your bedroom and
you'd think that your TV was off right
yeah I think I think again TV is
recording everything going on in your
bedroom right well another one of these
offensive cyber tools was the ability to
take control of a late model car using
its computer system Make It Go 100 miles
an hour without any intervention by
breaks or anything else and cause a
crash yeah now
um
it's actually quite easy you know it
could also be done on motorcycles I know
more about on motorcycles but yeah
John kirocco knows about motorcycles so
yeah you could tell that one anyhow what
I want to say is uh the rest of the
Susie's story is ironically explained I
think by volt seven uh documents and um
and that this is uh partly why uh the
new CIA director of Pompeo uh branded uh
Julian a
non-state terrorist outfit or is that
what they call them
yeah non-state hostile intelligence
agency and that's when they really
started going after him using the
Ecuadorian uh patsies to to get him out
Adam finally you know there's background
to that too uh which I didn't realize
until after the fact but if if the CIA
director declares an organization a
non-state
um actor then the law says that the
agency is exempt from Port from
informing the oversight committees if
there's an operation against it well you
know it's it's all like legalistic
[__] I mean you're you're making up
your rules so that you can follow these
new rules to get what you want so you
know it's it's legalistic [__] I I
can't think of a nicer term for this and
by the way you can curse all you want
this channel is demonetized I'm not
making a penny off of these videos so
you know cursor yeah you know although
Rey being a good Catholic boy he might
get get the vapors actually actually I
should revise that I made John 23 uh
Progressive Catholic and the pope and I
have very little in common except for
one thing
that is when in 2015
he had the guts to stand up before a
joint
Congress and say you know the main
problem is the blood-drenched arms trade
and all those congressmen get up and
said yes
see the latest envelope from Lockheed
and yeah
giving hypocrisy a bad name okay but he
had it
put a thumb on it
why he doesn't act on it is still
complicated but we don't wait for the
Poke attack these days we do it
ourselves but John to get back to your
point of calling Julian Assange a a
non-state intelligence service you know
I mean like
how how is it possible that people just
accept this because my thinking on the
Julian Assange show and I really want to
have Susie on but I I guess if
something's happened to her and she'll
be back all right there she is well I
want to bring the conversation to Julian
Assange because from my point of view
number one he has not committed any
crime in the United States number two
he's not a U.S citizen number three
whenever the the government documents
were released he was not in the United
States at the time so how on Earth can
you justify Prosecuting a man who didn't
commit a crime in the United States is
not a U.S citizen and the crime itself
is not committed on American soil I mean
yeah you're you're exactly right and I
think that's frankly the argument that
his attorneys are going to make too
besides the flat the fact that this is a
very very slippery slope
hang on John let me rephrase my question
why is it that the intelligence Services
hate this guy so much why him
specifically because I've never quite
understood there have been other leakers
all right I'm I'm saying this with with
uh respect of course you yourself were a
whistleblower and I'm sure a lot of
people at CIA were unhappy with you for
you know informing on the things that
you did but why is it that this guy
Julian Assange is hated so desperately
inside and such a psychopathic way what
was it that triggered this boundless
hatred for the man and we all have
different answers for that I've
definitely got one but take the floor
okay let's go piece by piece we'll go
we'll go John John Susie and Ray you
know just to keep some semblance Awards
by the way I'm gonna I'm gonna mute my
camera but I'm just going out to I'm
just smoking a cigarette I'm still here
okay go ahead please John so why do they
hate it I'm told that it's it's twofold
the reason is twofold uh first it's
because he was doing it with impunity he
was urging people to uh send documents
he was offering protection and and you
know he was taking talking uh people's
personal security very seriously they
were redacting documents to protect uh
the identities of people that just
enraged them the other thing and and I'm
told this is what sort of pushed the
agency over the edge was the release of
the Vault 7 documents uh those were the
most uh sensitive most important crown
jewels perhaps ever in the history of
the CIA that was just that was just too
much for them bridge too far so they've
gone after him like they have
but I mean it's been years now I mean he
was in that uh Ecuadorian prison for
what seven years I mean all together
this drama has been going on for 10. and
I mean how does anybody endure that that
that just
uh um that hatred for so long now Susie
you have a different View
well there's different sides to Julian
there's Julian the technologists and
software faculty who devised the first
ever encrypted Dropbox for
whistleblowers what later
um secure drop was modeled off of even
though some claim otherwise it was it
has proven to be
um there was Julian the Deep political
thinker who was a walking encyclopedia
who had studied so many tens of
thousands hundreds of thousands millions
of documents that he possessed a
uniquely
uh diverse and just profound
understanding of how the agencies worked
how the world worked how zero politics
work and was sharing that with other
people there was Julian my mentor and
the mentor of mini independent
Independent Media people he would take
people under his wing he would lift them
up he would platform them he would give
them a name give them exposure spread
their work share their work
um there was someone in that regard he
was always increasing the number of us
that were working on this type of thing
um but probably most importantly of all
and I think personally what they hate
him for the most is there's Julian who
is the only man on the planet who had
the ability to add a whim sees the
global media narrative when Julian was
free and working even when he was in the
Ecuadorian Embassy not really free but
still able to work
the Empire of Lies would have to chase
Julian's narrative Chase Wikileaks
narrative Chase Wikileaks work they were
never able to drive that narrative and
you see since they have seized Julian
kidnaps him from the embassy since they
have silenced him they have finally for
the first time and the better part of a
decade regained control of that
narrative and now they are driving the
narrative now all everything you see in
the media everything we're discussing
you know it's the Russia gate it's the
covert it's the whatever is next it's
Ukraine it's whatever this is all being
planned strategically planned and
devised and implemented by the people
who were on the back foot through all
those years of Julian's
um I nearly said Julian's Reign it was
Julian's reign in terms of control of
narrative and I cannot think of any
other person on this planet who is able
to direct the focus and attention of the
media class of the political class and
of the intelligence agencies the way
that he did and that made him uniquely
terrifying to them completely terrifying
and they also need they need to make an
example of him because their deepest
fear is the other Julians rise and
achieve the same thing and I'd like to
as my final thought on this point out
that Julian was the crash test I mean
for D platforming Julian was unpersoned
as you say before anybody else was
Julian was cut off from PayPal Julian's
bank cards were shut down Julian went
through the massive smear trolling
campaigns online defamation campaigns
Julian was subjected to the false
charges false allegations Julian was
hung out to dry first and that template
now we see being used against with
greater and greater frequency against
more and more people and that has now
become part of the for-profit model
there is now for-profit agencies that
not just Target for silencing but smear
anti-platform and every everybody is
being made into a Julian Assange because
they were able to get away with what
they did to him and now they think they
have free license so that is why they
hate Julian to the end of time
yeah Ray what are your thoughts
well I agree with everything that's been
said by Susie and by John and I have
other things that they hate him for
you know I'm I'm reminded of a
of my youth when we used to have Gene
Autry uh pictures okay and he used to be
driving he'd be riding through this uh
this terrible Rock fill landscape and oh
the iragosa Indians are over there they
hate you nut tree and they say why do
you hate they hate Gene Autry from
another picture
okay so the reason the powers that be
hate Julian Assange is from lots of
other pictures and I'll just fill in
some of the blanks that I think may
arise first off uh Julie Susie put her
her finger on it uh back when Julian
first appeared the fourth estate was
well on life support
the Foster state was as The Princess
Bride would say almost mostly then
mostly dead it was mostly okay and Here
Comes The Fifth Estate with an
instantaneous way of getting valid stuff
out into the ether and down into
computers whoa it was a difference in
kind okay it was a shock and what did
these things include not only war crimes
in Afghanistan or Iraq but things like
warnings
one specific one I'll sight warnings by
Sergey lavrov
the Russian foreign minister
on the first of February 2008
calling in Bill Burns
who ironically is now out of the CIA he
was Ambassador in Moscow okay call him
in as Mr Burns do you know what nietz
means
net if you allow Ukraine into NATO we
are going to have to retaliate because
this is this is a bridge too far we will
have to decide whether we have to inter
intervene invade Ukraine so please tell
your people tell your people this
congolesa rice at the time for God's
sake tell your people now Burns to his
credit played it straight which have the
cable if I've seen one cable from Moscow
Embassy I've seen about 8 000 of them
okay we have the cable Wikileaks made it
available that the title of Burns's
cable is niet means yet Russia's red
lines on Ukraine advancement into NATO
it went through the whole nine yards
suffice it to say that's really really
bad for the people who want it who want
to fool around with Ukraine want to fool
around with the west of the rest of
Eastern Europe now the couple other
things I'll be briefer here
um
2016. the unpardonable sin not mentioned
yet
but he published documents
from the Democratic National Committee
that showed that
show that Hillary had stolen the
nomination from Bernie Sanders pure and
simple yeah they were right there yeah
right there in black and white there's
another unpardonable sin okay that's
2016. now the other thing is Snowden
Ed Snowden what a patriot you know
what a patriot what he did okay now
Snowden got out of Hong Kong
Snowden happens to be a friend of mine
I've met him a couple of times he lives
pretty good life now he's got a little
boy they live in Russia let's just say
that okay now how was it
how was it that what everyone from the
CIA to it to the most to the least
liaison service was looking for for it's
a how do you get out I don't ever float
playing of all things it was surely a
Assange he called in all his chips from
that part of the world Susie probably
knows his brother and I do but well I'll
what I'll what I'll include here is a
little vignette last time I saw Julian
or maybe it was next to the last it was
in the embassy in Ecuador I said Julian
you know I admire a lot of things that
you've done all right but none more than
getting it snowed in out of out of Hong
Kong so it could be free
and Julian is not a he's sort of a tax
return person normally but he jumped off
the couch and he said
yes that a fellow like Ed Snowden would
not be not suffer the fate of so many
others so there again uh this was
against the the uh the Deep State and
finally as has been mentioned Vault
seven man that was just that was those
of the Family Jewels and everybody knows
about them now and that of course was
somebody who had some patriotic
instincts within the NSA
apparently according to what's been in
the price and gave them to Julian and
Julian was
circumspecting at first in publicizing
the ones but when negotiations for his
release fell apart and this is on very
good authority when people intervened
like the head of the Senate intelligence
committee intervene I said no no we're
not going to bargain with Julian Assange
he said all right the whole nine yards
gets released now and that's when you
got all virtually all of of all seven so
here there's a Litany of sins for which
uh for which Julian would be put in at
least Purgatory probably hell forever
together with Don Rumsfeld and all those
other guys uh if the Deep state had had
its way
I I I want to focus on both of those
issues that you raise array and so I'll
start with you Susie is how exactly did
Julian help Edward Snowden get to Moscow
because that seems to be a a spy story
and and I don't know if you guys know
that uh after college I got my start
writing in Hollywood and I wrote a
couple of Thrillers and I haven't
written a thriller since then but you
know this might make for a good thriller
so Susie could you fill us in on those
details
it's the best thriller really
um it was in hot water
it applied for Refugee status in Hong
Kong at
um Wikileaks suggestion edit had reached
out to WikiLeaks
um and it wanted to keep the distance
actually it made a lot of very Noble
decisions that were uh probably to his
detriment at the time
um but he wanted to keep distance
between himself and the the reporters he
didn't want to contribute in any way to
detracting from the potency of the
stories that were being reported based
on the documents which he had leaked so
he leaked when I say leaked I shouldn't
really used that term because it's not
really true he leaked to the journalists
for them to use their journalistic
skills and expertise to filter through
and to report on the content
um so he found himself somewhat adrift
in Hong Kong for a period of time and so
this has been covered extensively
elsewhere so I won't go too much into
detail he was taken care of by some
other asylums because is in Hong Kong
for a short period of time while there
was a literal Manhunt on for him yeah
and probably the extent and veracity of
that meant Hunter's not been reported on
so much to date but suffice it to say I
would say that half of the spies in
South Asia had been rerouted to Hong
Kong to go for him uh in that period of
time
and fortunately Julian decided to take a
few extra steps and first thing Haley
did was send an extremely Brave
journalist Sarah Harrison who was then a
Publications editor for Wikileaks to
Hong Kong to meet up with Snowden from
that point they got a really great legal
counsel International wise as well and
they managed to get
Snowden out of Hong Kong originally he
was to go to Ecuador via Cuba I believe
but that fell through by this point it
wasn't just uh spies on The Manhunt it
was International media leader as well
he had a slew of MSM reporters flying
various places around the world and
booking themselves on flights definitely
because desperately thinking that they
were going to be able to sit next to
Snowden and ask all the questions of
course Julian however had booked Snowden
onto Myriad flights on Myriad Airlines
to Myriad locations in order to obscure
snowden's actual path of Escape
he flew from Hong Kong it was quite
famously known I think that the US had
Frozen snowden's passport however they
had managed to misspell his middle name
in the order to cancel his passport and
so the Hong Kong authorities have said
we're sorry but this documentation is
actually not accurate therefore we can't
apply this order and um
it was a really brilliant press
statement actually put out by the Hong
Kong authorities at the time which
explained exactly how how this
administrative mistake had occurred
which had allowed Snowden to escape and
then and the next paragraph It said In
the meantime you know Snowden documents
expose you were spying on Chinese
University students blah blah blah so it
was absolutely hilarious obviously
somebody made a decision that um they
should buy the book to the documentation
which was inaccurate and therefore
allows known to leave uh Snowden was
transiting through Russia and um at that
point his passport was canceled red
notice was issued etc etc and he ended
up stuck in the transit lounge with
Sarah Harrison for some it was
definitely more than 30 days I can't
remember I want to say 36 or something
like that days here in the meantime he
applied for temporary Asylum and a large
number of countries all of which got the
U.S state Department called threatening
them with God knows what if they
accepted the temporary Asylum claim and
ultimately Russia granted him to
temporary Asylum because what else can
they do they can't let them live in the
airport for the rest of his life so
um and in the meantime of course Very
helpfully you had heads of U.S
intelligence agencies threatening to
kill him or jail him for his life on
International television which is pretty
good evidence for an asylum claim sorry
that's how that happened but it was
absolutely Julian Wikileaks Wikileaks
funds and network that were used to save
Stone's life and Julian did say on
multiple occasions that this was a
watershed moment it was important to
show
that if people were to take the brave
step of leaking of sharing the truth
with the public that there were others
and other avenues that would help and
assist them and that there would be an
opportunity for them to achieve some
level of safety and to and even to be
able to work in Snowden has done all
types of amazing and incredible work
since his life was so by Julian
while we're waiting for it go ahead Ray
go ahead Ray please you know
that's really really helpful that
background is essential I would add just
two small things
um
now when this unprecedented worldwide
investigation to try to find uh Ed
Snowden was in train they were looking
at all the likely places right I mean
they were looking in all the high rises
and all the fancy hotels in in Hong Kong
and they were looking among the Upper
Crust okay
thank you
Julian was nowhere to be found I mean Ed
was nowhere to be found he you know my
Irish grandmother told me about the
Upper Crust she said there's a bunch of
crumbs held together by a lot of dough
okay now no those crumbs
I'm gonna steal it by the way yeah
please yeah the Upper Crust a bunch of
crumbs held together by a lot of dough
okay well he was not among the Upper
Crust he was somewhere else this is no
secret now it's been sort of revealed
Julian had this incredible capability to
tap into what's needed you know and he
was a friend of oppressed people to
people living on the margins and people
not living in the high rises in Hong
Kong okay so that's that's another
little facet of the story I hope you'll
agree with that Susie okay the other
thing uh what's the other thing I was
gonna say oh yeah pooching up
I put you doesn't like Ed Snowden
well no he was asked you know uh he was
asked on film uh Mr President poochie do
you think that Ed Snowden did the right
thing
and Putin says no it didn't do the right
well then why did you give him uh why
did you give him
permanent sound now no well permanent
residency technically okay and now
citizenship got it but poaching said
well you know he didn't say what Susie
just said we're gonna leave him and shut
them yet to the airport forever he said
well uh nobody else would take them
and it's the right thing for for a
country to do to give political Asylum
and such cases so now why did Putin say
that no he didn't agree with what what
Ed Snowden did well for God's sake is is
the next kcb officer is he going to say
oh yeah
of course not
but when push came to shove he said I
followed at the national law here he
asked for Asylum nobody else would give
him Asylum everybody else was too afraid
of the United States I gave him Asylum
enough said yeah that's the issue I
wanted to raise with both of you and and
with John when he comes when he hops
back on
um do you guys think that this affected
uh uh the West's uh reaction towards
it's not or not not not the west but
rather the intelligence service that
they just had it in for Putin over
Julian over uh it's known that this
affect their their view of Putin or do
you think it was you know minor just a
blip on the road
I'm going to lean on the amazing MI6
whistleblower Annie Marshon who's the
only person that I've seen to date who
made the very astute observation that
the
vitriol the hatred with which with has
targeted Russia particularly since 2013
is a absolutely in direct relation to uh
them granting Asylum for Snowden
um that the whole Russia gate that
everything else that has been
you know
manufactured since then has been about
the defaming of Russia the
de-platforming of Russia that everything
else that we see is directly tied to
that that is the is it's not only for
that reason obviously there is
generations of beef underlying it but it
is absolutely a sticking point for them
and um such as I said in the case of
Julian they want to create a precedent
like they want to put the word out don't
even dare do this and of course they
have their own Workforce to worry about
and they were absolutely petrified post
noting that there would be other
snowdens from within the agencies and
they actually went to great they
introduced an entire like
um anti-snoden protocol where they
reworked all of their internal processes
and procedures to try and make sure that
they could identify the next Snowden
before he ever even got out of the
United States let alone to pass
documents here and anyone else Etc so
yeah I I absolutely believe that's a
Vector in this
and I respect greatly that um
all of the people and countries and
groups that have one way or another
helped to get to preserve Snowden for
the world for all of us and I I wish
that we could achieve the same thing for
Julian I very much wish that yeah and
it's the thing is see uh and I mean not
just respect to these two gentlemen when
when I say the following that see uh uh
Edward Snowden
um uh a brave man no question but the
fact is the information that he had
access to now that he is no longer in
the American intelligence service or an
intelligence service subcontract
uh his danger into the future is fairly
limited whereas I think there's a
perception that if Julian Assange were
let loose he'd continue with Wikileaks
encouraging more people to come forward
with abuses and illegalities and your
moralities and so I think that in in a
sense and and I don't mean this in in
any pejorative way but I think that
they're they're more afraid of Julian
Assange being free than Edward Snowden
being free do you see my rationale rate
would you agree
well I think it's hard to distinguish
these things
I would point out that again what what
Susie says is right on On Target any
Metro is one of the most astute
political observers I've run into
what there's another factor in broader
geo-strategic terms 2013
um you know in some ways this was the
apogee now you'd be surprised to hear
this probably but this was the height of
friendly U.S Russian relations yeah how
so yeah this before before the coup of
uh 14 13 14 in in yeah well this is 13
we're talking about and who change
pulled Obama's chestnuts out of the fire
Obama didn't want to start a war in
Syria he was under great pressure by all
his advisors and by Congress to do
precisely that poutine offered him a way
out to have those Syrian chemical
weapons destroyed under U.N supervision
on a U.S ship outfitted to destroy
chemical weapons that got Obama off the
hook to the point where the New York
Times on the 12th of September
2013 published an op-ed by Vladimir
which said you know our growing trust is
something I really relish not only the
trust between our countries but the
trust between our presidents President
Obama and myself the only thing I I
don't agree with President Obama on is
what he said last week that the U.S is
the sole exceptional country in the
world I don't think that makes sense I
there are there are poor Nations there
are nations close to the Microcenter I I
think that God looks on all these
countries and finds no exceptional one
finds them all to be equal now
that threw down the gauntlet to people
like Victoria Noland and all these other
growing trust growing drugs
six months later we have the coup in
Kiev on the maiden and you know the rest
of that story so you know it was uh you
know it was certainly Ed played into
this but also the geopolitical things
here where you had the budding trust
here Obama grateful for it and Obama not
willing or able just to stand up to the
likes of
Victorian old and John Brennan and the
rest of the deep state which is a very
real entity
yeah I I mean this whole situation from
the world view of the Russians that they
helped them out in a serious situation
and all the rest is building trust and
then six months later they manufacture
the coup in in Kiev that was the wake-up
call for for the Russians that was when
they realized hey we're going to have a
war with these people so we have to
postpone this war so that we can prepare
and here we are you know in in the
middle of it
um I I wanted to bring I I wanted to
toss a question to John but John is
still not back with us but let me let me
intervene here it's not that the
Russians had to prepare
it's that NATO had to prepare a fighting
force
to force the Russians out of dunbas
we know what happened now John Brennan
John Brennan went to Amos yeah right
after the coup and the idea was okay uh
we're gonna rebuild your forces we're
going to train ten thousand uh people uh
each each year and then we're going to
take back the dunbas and we're going to
threaten Russia okay now that's that's
what was in play here and Putin uh was
trying through what we'll call the Minsk
Accords uh which Ukraine had signed up
to and which Germany and France had
guaranteed which would have given these
provinces in the East uh vignetsk and
Logan's a measure of our autonomy under
the new Constitution that went by the
board and we have the former prime
minister of Ukraine owning up to the
fact that they were never taken Minsk
seriously it was just a stratagem to
postpone the years until they could get
trained up so that they could think on
the Russians and that happened what
2014 uh 2021 so you got six or seven
years uh and that's why Russia uh faced
a much more vulnerable folk than anyone
expected including perhaps the Russians
well no that that's uh
I think that the Russia Russians had a
very very clear idea at the beginning of
this conflict now in 2022 as to what
they were dealing with and they were
very well prepared for it and uh the the
proof is in the pudding because people
in the west have noticed uh don't quite
understand
um how this war has been prosecuted and
it's been this very slow grinding
process because it's been a deliberate
strategy of the Russian army to just
slowly be grinding away as opposed to
trying to make any dramatic and
spectacular move because they realize
that politically uh it's to their
advantage to make it a slow grinding
process that in essence bores the West
because after seven months people are at
the end of their tether and of course
with the loss of energy resources Europe
in particular is is
you know going through Dire Straits and
it's going to get a lot worse in the
winter and so the the way the Russians
have been handling this war has been uh
very effective uh but I wanted to go
back to
um the the famous Vault seven that you
and John
um mentioned a couple of times and I
don't know what what's happened to John
I hope that you know he sorts out his
Communications issues because I really
wanted to bring him in what were these
crown jewels of Vault seven I mean first
of all what is Vault seven and what is
what's in it and what was released
specifically that just made the CIA and
the intelligence Services of the United
States throw a hissy fit
so that I intro at Ray and new Gap Phil
okay go go okay I'm sorry
oh I said I'll intro the Publications
and and you can get Phil on whatever yes
oh yes you are
oh my gosh
um okay so Vault seven was a Wikileaks
publication of a large case of documents
that had been supplied to them by a
whistleblower who some people think was
Joshua Schulte who is unfortunately an
extremely parallelistic consensus in a
U.S black site slash prison right now
and on you know on U.S soil he's an
American citizen CIA whistleblower we
don't uh Julian would never confirms or
uh denies who the source of a Wikileaks
publication is so that's why I kind of
go around the issue there I can't
definitively say one way or the other
um as to who is the source but that's
who many people believe to be the source
can you repeat the name please Joshua
salty it's c h u l t e am I correct
correct and he was CIA
he would have been a CIA contractor
um one of the bums on seats that John
karaoke was telling you about before
um he has been arrested he has um been
accused of uh possessing child
pornography which is this strange charge
that somehow seems to be applied to a
multitude of whistleblowers that end up
leaking files or documents uh Joshua
Schultz is not the only leaker who has
somehow then
um had the accusation labeled at him but
obviously they're far more concerned
about whether or not he actually leaks
these documents so
um Wikileaks always themed and named
their Publications so that they could
um promote and get the most uh possible
views for them which they did very
successfully so Vault 7 is the name that
they branded that publication they
released a series of uh very enigmatic
images that cost about a six week period
to let people know something was going
to drop and then this these documents
hit
um the documents contained a number of
absolutely shocking revelations actually
part of that was about the ability for
intelligence agencies to hack and
comment their vehicles as Ray was
mentioning earlier another one which I
won't talk much about because I know
it's Ray's favorite topic is the marble
framework in which this it laid out the
cia's um
method of impersonating Russia North
Korea and and there was royalty who the
the third was
um because China Chinese uh win their
perpetrating hacks and penetrations of
networks so they would disguise
themselves as being a Chinese
intelligence agency or a Russian
intelligence agency etc etc and this was
their whole framework for how how
precisely to do that at a technical
level
um there was all types of things about
zero day exploits of major commercial
software platforms and operating systems
devices Etc one of the big Revelations
particularly for activists and
independent journalists and anyone who
was using
um encrypted into and encrypted
messaging applications was the cia's
ability to completely bypass encrypted
messaging systems on your mobile device
so that they would penetrate to your
device at the hardware level and
therefore um operating system and
therefore any encryption that was
occurring in application after that
sorry too late they're already recording
every single keyboard stroke so there is
no and I just like to be very clear
there is no encrypted messaging
application in or email service which
provides you any type of personal
protection if you are in any way
targeted and if you're not all of those
comms are getting drag knitted anyway
because they will store the encrypted
data packets for the day in the future
that they will then be able to Via
Quantum Computing or otherwise break the
encryption protocols if they can't we'll
really do that which they may well be
able to we just don't know yet so
unfortunately you can have privacy from
like you know some script Kitty down the
road who might try and hack you but
you're not going to get privacy from the
CIA and we've learned that definitively
from Vault seven there had been some
questions prior to that as to whether or
not there was some degree of security
for users
um and that was just completely blown
apart by Vault seven
um but there were other revolutions and
marble framework in particular was very
significant in terms of other things
that were happening in politics and
media and then I will hand you over to
the expert on that array right now oh by
the way I'm I'm I'm still here I'm just
uh moving to a better lighting Source
because I looked a little too Darth
Vader kind of like Dark Night of the
Soul kind of thing so anyway Susie go
ahead what about marble what is marble
well I have to admonish Susie for
spilling the marbles here
um
and Susie has already indicated uh you
know this gave
um
this gave the CIA with lots of help from
NSA we're talking about a billion
billion billion dollar program here okay
uh my friends uh from NSA were there
when this was started so NSA and CIA
were in there together now mobile
framework uh allowed uh people to
fiddle around with uh some of the
evidence and make it seem uh that this
or that intercept or whatever you call
it uh came from North Korea
or Russia or China
or Iran or an Arabic country they worked
in five languages okay now we all
remember all the charges about uh
Russian fingerprints
on some of those
some of those terrible
interventions in the the uh the election
of
2016. that was all hogwash oh yeah some
of it had to do with this uh uh this
capability to uh impute blame to Russia
China North Korea Arabic countries or
Iran but others were just clearly
discoverable by people like Susie who
had the expertise but yeah mobile
framework was big and I mentioned before
that when this uh when this came out it
only came out uh because uh as I
understand it and and since you may know
more there had been an attempt in early
March actually it started around
February of 2017 I believe where Julian
was was willing to tell the justice
department
who didn't give
those uh that terribly damaging
information on Hillary and everybody
else uh and in in return for a measure
of Freedom uh measure of not being you
know and the negotiations were at a
Tipping Point when some
some dumb lawyer
who knew the vice head of the Senate
intelligence committee Senator Mark
Warner
he said well hey Senator Warner do you
know about this uh do you know that
there's this trade going on between the
justice department acting and as a agent
of CIA and Wikileaks people you know
about that and want to say no nobody
told me that totally looked into it he
immediately called Comey head of the FBI
at the time Comey told the justice
department shut that down we're not
going to give Julian uh any any measure
of comfort now
it was just a week later if memory
serves that Julian said okay here it
goes the rest of Vault seven was
released correct me if I'm wrong uh
Susie
I wouldn't
say that it was punitive the rest of the
release because Julian was extremely
committed to maximizing the scale of
Publications and putting as much out
there as possible
um you are correct that there were
indications on being very like politic
here there were indications
um that he was for the first time ever
prepared to not say who did it but who
didn't do it and we know who didn't do
it and we know and in this case it's a
country rather than a person that didn't
do it and we
um
we know that that was absolutely
derailed at the highest levels just as
the engineering of Julian's exposure
expulsion from the Ecuadorian Embassy
was similarly
um orchestrated at the highest levels
um I'm not particularly convinced that
it would necessarily make a difference
one way or the other I don't really what
makes me say that is Trump's failure to
Pardon Snowden or as such
um and yeah he might have got on the
wrong side of Trump by rejecting Trump's
officially not an emissary of trump that
was sent to be an emissary of trump to
the Ecuadorian Embassy
um but
uh we we can't say definitively but
certainly the timeline of events and the
events are as Ray described
um absolutely
no I mean this whole situation of uh
juliusange Edward Snowden you know of
course they fell on them like a ton of
bricks to worn off anybody else but I
has it been effective because
um as far as I know and I'm not as on
top of this as you both are uh has there
been any kind of leak like the Julian
Assange and Edward Snowden leaks well
yeah I mean the
correct I mean Susie made the point uh
that a lot of this was to preempt what
uh right happened what uh Ed Snowden did
from anybody else doing it but Ed
Snowden was 2013 right yeah
volt 7
2017 right so I mean there still are
good people around willing to take great
risks to make sure that that we're
informed about some of the mojinos
things going on now I don't know if it
was Schulte or anybody else but uh this
this attempt to make sure that this
never happened again fail I witnessed
the fact we have Schulte and hopefully
others that will speak out people of the
character of John kiriako who will speak
out on a matter of principle so you
can't shut good people down forever and
uh and the proof is in the pudding they
can try and they are pretty effective
intimidating a lot of people I give you
a little example here that I people
probably don't know about about two
months ago I said to myself McGovern you
know a good bit about Russia China
Ukraine uh you know the history of all
this because you're so old for God's
sake
um look why don't you do a little why
don't you ask somebody to interview you
and let you speak for an hour about how
all this happened okay
and Regis Tremblay a uh a videographer
said okay ray I'll do that for you uh
and he did on the 6th of July I called
it uh a taste of the truth
and I took it through my experience
there as a CIA analyst early in the 60s
and so forth all the way down and I and
I pointed out that look you know I
learned a hell of a lot at government
expense here's my way of of giving back
believe it or not but this is what I
experienced this is what I know okay
called it a taste of the truth
it got up on YouTube
it got all of a sudden 26 000 views
YouTube shut it down
so a taste of the truth was too much for
YouTube well luckily it was saved on bit
shoot in a couple other places but this
it doesn't speak volumes that that the
taste of the truth is a little bit too
much tasty for for YouTube so this is
how it is going here uh it's harder for
people to to see what I say or what I
write uh but you know it's still
available and I'm still hopeful well we
do what we can you know there are
reverses but we don't stop and uh you
know one of my one of the things that
I'm asked very often McGovern for God's
sake
don't you get tired I mean you've been
doing this for what 20 years now since
you told that you told us all there were
no weapons of mass destruction why did
God go to that too don't check your
tires so I tell them this little story a
good friend of mine he was a
representative from Wisconsin his name
was Dave Obi okay he's a good guy he
went to church together okay so he's
headed the Appropriations Committee okay
but before that during Iran Contra he's
really upset that Schultz and Reagan and
the others didn't tell him about Iran
Contra so he brings Schultz toward the
end of this investigation brings him in
to it to appear before a subcommittee
and he says now uh
Secretary of State Schultz I would like
to question you about this and Schultz
very uncharacteristically says
Congressman Obi
the American people is just they're just
sick and tired of this Iran gate and
nobody doesn't admits of bread he looks
down at Schultz and he says Mr Schultz
I didn't swear to support and protect
the constitution in the United States
from all enemies foreign and domestic
until I got tired
that's the way it is with us okay we
took that same oath
and well even even though the odds are
against this we don't get tired and
maybe maybe we'll come to a no good end
but it isn't because we get tired
well what's happened to me what I find
deeply disturbing about this whole
situation is that this kind of
repression of uh leakers and whatnot it
spreading like a cancer and uh because
what you said Susie in that video that I
I watched of yours it was like an hour
long video where you went through a
whole host of different issues and and
the notion that these companies of
repression are expanding and expanding
not just into intelligence to prevent
leaks whether you agree with that or not
it's understandable at least that they
would want to prevent leaks from their
own agency but now they are expanding
out to silence people who say the wrong
thing who say the thing that they don't
agree with or who highlight information
that is publicly available but that they
they want to tune down they don't want
people to hear as much of and this kind
of repression is spreading out and
nobody is safe and it's becoming deeply
creepy that uh so many people now
regular civilians quote unquote feel
nervous about touching certain topics
because there are afraid of the
repercussions that they that could
befall them that that you know they
could lose their job or contracts or or
business opportunities or educational
opportunities it it just seems deeply
bizarre and it's not just intelligence
it's also things that are properly the
purview of personal belief or political
opinion that is
frankly inconsequential to the National
Security of a nation and and so that's
what where the part for me uh uh has
really changed because it's sort of like
um the scope of this repression and and
cutting off leaks has expanded and the
remittance has gone global and and that
I find deeply disturbing because I
myself uh I'm a nobody I'm a stupid
middle-aged YouTuber who's doing these
videos for fun
this is an amusement for me it's like
wait a second there Gonzalo you went to
an Ivy League school uh
when they accepted me away don't don't
try to disguise the fact that you have
very good pedigree all right so you're a
pretty bright guy so to go after you
they have good reason
yeah Ray tone down the the thing I I
promise you 20 bucks after the show for
sending those things
Ray's done his homework I said I'm not
surprised at all
um no but but the thing you see like
what's happened to me I I did a a solo
live stream yesterday about this
particular issue is that in last uh the
last couple of weeks you know I got uh
suspended from YouTube I I got my
Twitter
um you know
eliminated does it permanently suspended
add 70 000 viewers and it was because I
was uh saying that the Europeans had
essentially committed suicide and you
know that was enough to get me the
platform from Twitter uh and also
um back in April I was uh I was I was
arrested and held by the state Security
Services of the Ukraine and uh they took
my accounts and and what have you um
because I I used to have a fairly large
Channel about 300 000 subscribers and
another one of 150 000 and a Twitter
account of 60 odd thousand people and I
lost access to all that stuff and that
Twitter account for instance which I had
not had access to since the 15th of
April that too was deleted I mean it
just to unperson me it was deeply creepy
no worries no worries Gonzalo nobody
please tell us all about pankoy
hahaha
damn it I wanted to start at censorship
and then to get into the deep
platforming and then before we talk
about pancake I'll tell you a few things
you don't know about pancake in fact I
might just um tell the whole world
something that I know about pancake uh
pancake delivery is happening
um regardless of what happens in terms
of crowdfunding though please do donate
at pancake.com
as soon as the broadcast is over I'll
have those links in the description
below chat so
3700 ordinary members of the public who
are sick of getting arbitrary
suspensions and Shadow bands and sending
messages and not knowing if anyone will
even be able to see them and having
moderation actions taken against them
with no transparency about what the
networks are doing and are thirsty for a
not just right or not just left or not
you know partisan platform and actually
want to be able to put their voice out
and be free of the commercial
constraints and not have the data
captured and sold to corporations and
Big Data companies and security agencies
which happens every single day came
together and they raised a hundred and
eighty three thousand dollars uh us and
they funded pancake which is pancake.com
which is a new platform that's going to
free us of all of the constraints that
we have been facing now of course we're
going to be a massive Target of course
we're going to it was funny someone was
saying to me um yesterday well what if
YouTube does this to you and what if
Google does this to you and I said to
them I don't think about that when I'm
doing my security planning I think about
targeted access operations at the NSA
and what they're going to do to me I
don't know what YouTube is going to do
to me but the YouTube stuff the lawyers
can worry about but our architecture our
thread assessment model is slightly
different than just like YouTube but
what we're trying to do is give well
what we are in fact doing we've already
built our interface and we're now just
doing our back end Integrations so we
can release our betas to the public is
to give people cryptographic proofs of
the action taken on the network via the
blockchain including our actions as the
network provider which means if we ban
someone if we suspend someone if we
remove some child porn or whatever off
our Network which we absolutely will
remove be all clear about that there is
a cryptographic proof on our blockchain
that we took this action against this
account on this day at this time this is
the reason why this is the moderator ID
that did it so that we are bringing
transparency to we'll just change it
we're fixing the power imbalance between
the platform and the user right it
shouldn't be all about the focus on the
user I actually need the focus on the
platform so the whole network will know
what we as the provider do and can hold
us accountable for that but they also
have cryptographic proof of their
actions that they take when they publish
public content so so if 50 people like
your Quake message on pancake there are
50 blockchain transactions to prove that
those people click that like button on
that piece of content so we can't come
along and unlike it or unretweet you
know and and share it we can't we can't
violate the actions taken by the users
on our Network in the shadows which is
what's happening right now because I am
seeing I am seeing absolutely hands down
call me a conspiracy theorists if you
want I'm seeing manufactured statistics
on Twitter they can decide how many
retweets they want to be on something
they can decide how many likes they want
to be on something they can decide
whether or not you see it the other
thing about paintwork is it is algorithm
free your timeline is in chronological
order you see only content by the people
who you followed so it's completely
opt-in for user content if you didn't
follow the account you don't see this
stuff if you unfollow them you don't see
their stuff we don't recommend stuff we
don't um use any personalization
algorithms we don't decide what we think
you might like and stick it in front of
you we have no advertising no sponsored
content nothing like that you can't buy
space on pan on a pancake timeline there
is no mechanism by which people can pay
us for that and in all we do ask because
we don't sell your data we don't capture
your data it's a peer-to-peer Network
you exchange your data with other people
your account data is on your device all
we ask is that people pay five bucks a
month per user that's it so you pay a
five dollar a month subscription and you
are free of advertising free control
we're registered outside of U.S
jurisdiction we don't use any U.S
infrastructure or infrastructure of the
Empire as a whole we are domiciled and
independent some of the last independent
jurisdictions on Earth and our Network
hosting is there as well we also don't
capture image or video content and
another date we'll talk about how the
technology if you're interested just go
look up pen quick on YouTube you'll find
plenty of stuff now I've kind of done
this in reverse order because I wanted
to talk about the censorship problem
first rather than talk about pancake
um because what I I'm finding deeply
disturbing is that all of these uh big
platforms the big gun monopolistic
platforms uh number one they are
deliberately kept as monopolies and they
are protected by the other players the
other Monopoly players uh number two
what I've I've started seeing is that
you're seeing a
government-sponsored trolling going on
on on uh on Twitter it's been a big
thing it started with uh the Ukrainian
situation and it's been expanding and
I'm noticing it that it's happening in
different nuclei of Interest where you
have paid trolls that Twitter allows
where anything else they would you know
ban them immediately but these are the
approved trolls the Servants of Empire
yeah exactly they're they're like the
NGO are minions in some countries
starting up a uh a color Revolution you
know what I'm saying and they're in
Twitter and they attack and mass uh
anybody who's saying things that counter
the narrative uh and so it's it's much
more interesting than merely trying to
suppress information it's trying to
discredit it and
um uh uh make it vanish Into The Ether
so that it just doesn't have a chance to
percolate it's it's like when Mark
Zuckerberg went on Joe Rogan and he
admitted that he
um he he for he made Facebook suppress
the Joe Biden laptop story or the hunter
Biden laptop story uh prior to the
election at the behest of the FBI I mean
this would have been outrageous not 10
years ago uh but now it has been
completely normalized and and that part
of it I there was less shock over that
that is the thing I find shocking and
the government is acting in ways that
are totally fascistic the the
um and as I said before I am a political
conservative and I'm calling it
fascistic and they are the the companies
are going along with this because
they're the they depend on the
government for money they don't want to
make enemies they're playing it safe
um at best they are acting amorally if
you will but the government is certainly
the US government is certainly acting
immorally and you're right the Empire
my my feeling is that especially as the
geopolitical situation begins to
deteriorate further and further for the
United States insofar as having
perceived losses geopolitically that the
repression will intensify I mean if if
people think that the repression is bad
now wait five years it's going to be
much much worse that's my thinking at
this point you Susie see yeah sorry my I
actually haven't been on Twitter for a
while now because I spent all my days
working day and night but on my Twitter
bio
um I say like surveillance censorship is
a for-profit model and that's what I see
so I see that um we talked about the
subcontractors the pyramid scheme of
surveillance Contracting
um and now what I see is the formation
of a pyramid scheme of censorship so it
used to be that these security
contractors would get paid to create
spreadsheets of hundreds of names of
Twitter users and put them forward to
the agencies to check them out and
decide you know how they want to handle
these people what what level of
targeting are these people who want to
do
um now I see exactly the same processes
being used and the same security
contractors being used where the goal is
censorship and suppression of speech
rather than just the pure political the
physical political targeting I just did
want to tell you something just that you
said before you're saying you know just
why me I'm just like some guy I used to
have the same sensation all the time I
was a single man from the suburb with
two kids all I did was go to a activism
movement and try and help feed people
and look after people and get their
messages out like why me and um first of
all there is because they make money
from doing this to you and secondly
because their end goal is to do this to
everyone Mass surveillance is about
collecting all the information all the
data all the communication so even if I
am not an activist or a journalist or
whatever I can still be in that Dragnet
and they bill Benny I'm now going to
trample over all over Bill Benny's
ground age so it's been a couple of
hours with him a few days ago Ray
um he always talks about the two degrees
of separation and how actually for every
one target there are thousands of
targets because they target every single
person you know or have any connection
to an any way in your life and then they
target all of the people that they know
as well so literally I mean I come from
and you you know country of New Zealand
five million people we had 80 known
targets of the gcsb our spy agency
through the time that I was an activist
including kim.com was a major one on
that list
um 18 new zealanders how many people
They Know Each 100 200 each okay well
how many did they know each 100 200 each
250 each
how hard is it to get those two hops to
cover the entire friggin country on one
surveillance warrant and they do these
bulk collection warrants now the
collection warrants are the intelligence
agencies aren't on an individual it's
not on Susie from occupy it's on the
city of Auckland that internet service
provider whatever they call them bulk
collection warrants they can nominate a
company a geographic location or get to
this they use this word a class of
people
oh that's a class of people they can get
a book collection warrant on so this
really does affect everybody whether
it's because you know someone who knows
someone that is of interest to them they
will rate through your entire life
whether it's because you happen to be in
a location that is of interest to them
or whether you are part of a class of
people what is that is there students at
a university is that people at a church
is that like what is that class of
people we don't really know we know that
the leader um the head of the agency of
the gcsb
um says that he spends a dozen hours you
know going and getting these warrants
but then when they publish the warrant
statistics there any of this tiny little
number that they that they have um that
they admit to having per year so if you
have a tiny number of warrants but you
spend all these hours at Parliament
getting those warrants and you can place
warrants on a geographic location or
class of people what does it add up to
it adds up to we're all victims the only
question is whether you know it or not
um and um I completely agree we I mean
we're past the point of needing another
church committee like we need a freaking
Nuremberg for these people because well
we haven't we have what we haven't got
to yet is that surveillance kills
surveillance kills if you are under
surveillance and you know it it damages
your mental health it damages your
relationships they interfere in every
aspect of your life they literally kill
people they drive them to suicide in
some cases they actually do much worse
things that I don't even want to really
talk about but yeah at least yeah I mean
well the classic example
exactly right when I heard that story I
was like no they crashed his car and no
no
it's like the the you know the two
bullets in the back of the head and it's
called suicide you don't know that that
was most definitely absolutely
yeah they manipulated the um the
automobile by the by the way there were
some interesting data um this uh actress
who who was killed recently and H
there's video evidence of her trying to
stop the car as it was like carooming at
60 miles an hour in some Los Angeles
Suburban Street
and uh it went by some security camera
and you could hear the sound and and if
you're mechanically inclined and know
anything about cars you could hear how
the handbrake had been pulled on the car
because when when you drive a car with
the handbrake uh which is not designed
to do it makes a very distinctive sound
it was clearly that that this poor
woman's car was had been tampered with
and she was corrobing at you know 60 odd
miles an hour 70 miles an hour through
the Suburban Street and eventually
crashed and apparently was killed uh uh
and you know this kind of thing crazy as
it may sound because I'm not one for
conspiracy theories you know I do
believe that Paul is alive and Elvis
dead and Neil Armstrong walked on the
moon but some of the things that come up
you're like no come on come on that
that's that's not how that happened I
mean come on I'm you know I I I didn't
fall off the tournament truck you know
yesterday it was you know the week
before last but still it's been a while
enough that I'm not that damn stupid you
know but they they consistently push
narratives that are so absurd and they
expect everyone to believe them they
they use their positions of authority to
uh um you know that they're part of the
mainstream media and and whatnot so that
you're sort of like
you you feel impolite to disagree and I
think that that's one of the problems
that we're having Ray
uh Gonzalo a proposed of all this
what happened to John kiriakov I don't
know what happened to him I know you
know he actually he actually emailed his
apologies his internet went out oh it
was choppy and then it was gone
no he's safe I did yeah he's safe I did
suggest to him that uh he have he seek
an alternative method of connecting and
hopefully he will come back um I know
he's here with us yeah because uh look
uh the standing offer to John if he's
listening that we will I'll be happy to
have him on again at another opportunity
because it was a delight to talk for him
forever briefly
yeah
yes how come I don't hear any uh Rockets
or bombings or anything like that what
have you to add from your pers your
specific uh message Point well um let me
see on September 9th Friday September
9th there was a big strike here in
um in the city of Kharkov they hit a
number of targets they were all about a
dozen targets or a little over a dozen
targets uh within you know minutes of
each other
um it was simultaneous clearly a Russian
I don't know what I mean it was Russian
no question
and um they actually hit one of the
buildings next to mine
I have pretty spectacular pictures but I
can't share them because it shows the
karkov skyline and you could identify or
figure out uh where I'm at and I want to
keep that information private for the
time being uh but um yeah it was it was
um very spectacular but after that and
there were also two blackouts that day
Friday that evening there was a blackout
for about six hours and then on Tuesday
Tuesday last a week uh ago today there
was another six hour blackout but since
then there hasn't been any blackouts uh
there have been various theories as to
why uh the Russians would have taken out
the electrical Grid in um in in just
about the whole country
um one very shrewd observation that was
made was that this was during the
so-called heart club offensive and uh
Russian forces might have wanted to slow
down the movement of troops because you
see the
um train system works on electricity and
so
um knocking out the power no trains Ergo
you can't move troops and tanks and so
it might have been that or it might have
been a show of force or whatever other
reason and the Russians
um I I mean I I know uh I I know enough
of the Russian military at least that
they don't go to the bathroom without a
plan and they don't do things for no
reason they have very very good reasons
for just about everything that they do
and so if if they did this approach of
knocking out the lights twice but not
bothering after that even though they
could do it whenever they want they must
have had a specific reason for it it
wasn't just you know uh
um to um quote unquote terrorize the
population because in fact these two
um blackouts were the only blackouts
have been the only blackouts here in the
city of Kharkov since the beginning of
this conflict or more properly since I
arrived here on the 1st of March because
between the 24th of February and the
first of March I was in Kiev and um and
there weren't any blackouts there either
um uh you know and I came on the first
of March and since then until September
9th the the electricity internet
Everything Mobile phones everything
worked perfectly fine until Friday the
9th for six hours and then uh Tuesday
the 13th for six hours and since then
it's been relatively quiet
um I don't know what is going on
um except what I get from publicly
available sources because you know I'm a
chicken and I just want to stay away
from the bullets and the artillery
shells because they're horrifying and I
don't want any piece of that you know
and and the the people who have had to
suffer a lot of damage and whatnot
because of this conflict you know my
hearts go out to them but uh uh yeah I I
try to stay away from all that and the
information I get really is from the
internet
and I'm saying here
um I originally came here because uh my
my wife and my children are here I had
gone to Kiev on business I literally
arrived the night before I was supposed
to be there just for two nights and then
come back but I was stuck there for a
bit and took the train down here
um and uh my wife and children they have
already left they spent the summer in
Western Europe and they had a lovely
time and I stayed here helping out my
in-laws and just you know and and now
quite frankly uh because of my situation
with the sbu they've asked me not to
leave the city
and um and these they told me that if I
try to leave the country they'll know
about it because they'll check me at the
border and that I'll be arrested and so
that's why as a practical matter I
really can't leave
um and uh yeah I'm staying here and
quite frankly I want to see what happens
I want to see how this uh this situation
plays out I'm very very surprised that
it has lasted as long as it has I mean
if you had told me on February 24th that
we'd be into September and this would
still be going on I would have been
truly shocked because I would have
thought that they would have negotiated
a ceasefire and some sort of agreement
and the hostilities
but
um the zonski regime clearly has no
intention of doing that their intent on
fighting to The Bitter End and I think
it's going to be extremely bitter I I
think that um
from the very beginning wasn't has to
understand two things number one this
was an existential War for Russia
they had to prevent Ukraine from joining
NATO and and they and and they certainly
were not going to allow Ukraine to
invade the donbass as they were planning
to number one and that's the first truth
and number two uh the Russian armed
forces are simply better equipped they
have more manpower and they are better
LED
and better supplied than the Ukraine
Armed Forces so when you have two
unequal fighters in a ring the result is
inevitable and there's simply no contest
when you have a bantam weight going up
against a heavyweight there's no
question as to what's going to happen
and you see if you have and to continue
the metaphor if you have the manager of
the bantamweight keep it keeps on
telling him keep on going keep on
fighting you'll win against Mike Tyson
here in front of you
you are the one who are going to be hurt
and hurt in a way that you won't recover
from and that's the tragedy of the
Ukraine situation they have been goaded
by the West into a war that will destroy
Ukraine destroy a generation of
ukrainians
and because of the Exodus of people
especially the most educated people the
most hard-working people those people
have fled to the west where they were
received with open arms which is all
very nice and good but see they will
have no incentive to return to Ukraine
after the hostilities are over and it's
credibly estimated that something like
11 million people have left Ukraine a
country of 44 million roughly a quarter
of the population has fled the country
some 3 million or a little bit more than
3 million has fled to Russia and the
rest to the west and those people will
never return
how about the uh how about the folks uh
that are still there in haka for example
um is there any War weariness or are
they uh the Patriotic ukrainians or uh
you know how's the man in the street
feel about this Darren
I have a very little uh limited contact
with uh people but I can say that um for
the most part in March the city was
empty I mean I'm talking empty if you
had told me that 80 of the population
had fled the city I would have said yeah
that sounds about right perhaps more
um but now there's a lot of life in the
city a lot of people have come back you
see cars on the roads and going in
different places I mean it seems
semi-normal-ish there are lots of
restaurants that are open and so forth a
lot of businesses though are permanently
closed
um I suspect
okay this is my suspicion but it's it's
fairly it's fairly correct that the
people who came back are Russian ethnic
Russians pro-russia and so that's why
they're here I think that there is the
fundamental expectation that eventually
Russia will take the city
uh because the people who were truly
pro-ukrainian who were Ukrainian ethnic
Ukraine's they've left them they are not
coming back to Kharkov this I know for a
fact of certain acquaintances that I
know who are ethnically Ukrainian and
and and and are very anti-russian and
they have no intention of coming back
and so I think that a lot of people who
have come back and who are trying to go
get on with their lives are people who
fully expect themselves to be Russian
citizens within the next year or two uh
and and that is an incredible
possibility because the cities that have
been captured by Russia they've offered
uh the people there to get a Russian
passport and Russian citizenship and
it's a very simple bureaucratic process
the line sometimes can be long but
apparently the process itself takes you
know 15 minutes and you leave there with
a Russian passport
yeah or well actually you leave with a
ticket and you'll get the Russian
passport but you know what I mean
um but but the thing is see
um
this is a civil war
okay and
um and people are choosing signs and
Kharkov is a Russian city it is a
traditionally Russian city it is a
majority ethnic Russian uh everybody
speaks Russian here unlike in the west
where they speak Ukrainian and so yeah
the the expectation is that this will
eventually fall to the Russians that's
the expectation at this time good yeah
I'm gonna have to leave in about 10
minutes uh yeah we're gonna wind it down
because it's been a great conversation
but you know there's the the song by
Michelle shocked the secret to A Long
Life Is Knowing When it's time to go so
anyway on that I want to invite you both
to give like a final
um note uh as to the topic that we've
been discussing here
um I should have prepared you before and
told you about it but is there anything
that you want to leave The Listener with
and any final thought that you think
would be worthwhile for them to carry
with them uh after the end of the show
Susie can I throw it to you please
all this so much so much
that is so much having read thousands of
Snowden documents I have a head full of
knowledge that I wish that the average
person had and I can only encourage them
to
um and this goes for Wikileaks documents
too to go to WikiLeaks and actually
search key terms and educate yourself
because a man sacrificed his life and
many other lives have one way or another
been impacted by it for the knowledge
that is sitting in that database just
waiting for people to to consume learn
about how the world really works and in
those documents you'll find them because
when you read the documents of the
agencies you get a completely different
picture than you get watching some you
know CNN produced like short documentary
about them the media does not tell you
the truth about how these agencies work
um it's probably a whole other show for
me to share what I know about the inner
workings of these agencies it's actually
something I would love you to learn
about Gonzalo because I think it
originally impacts your life and when
you uh when you obtain this type of
knowledge there are
ways in which you can alter your choices
and
um in your own life which will put you
in a slightly better position than you
would otherwise have been so to be a
Target like you obviously are and I feel
great solidarity with you because your
life is at risk that's a fact and you
are a Target that's a fact
for you I would love you to learn as
much as you can in order to empower
yourself in your own situation
and Julian did exactly that he empowered
targets to better be able to survive
their own situation
um in terms of final messages I just
want to say I love Roman government so
much she's one of my favorite people and
the person is on it I call him great if
you want me to leave so I can leave you
two alone together I don't know
the reason one of the reasons I love
them so much is because he reminds me of
my grandfather who was a World War
cricketer and and who fought from 39
until most nearly all the way through 44
my grandfather and his brother went to
war and only my grandfather came home
and Ray reminds me very much of my
grandfather and so I've always just felt
a natural Affinity to him for that
reason but also because he's a walking
encyclopedia like Julian and when Ray
talks I feel like I can sit here and
listen all night because just as
Wikileaks is a great resource and just
as the snowing documents are a great
resource sitting here and listening to
Rey and his experiences and his
knowledges similarly a resource like
that
um so yeah they really don't have much
else to say except thank you to for
having me on the show oh my pleasure I
mean somebody whenever you want to
please well um yeah I'd love to talk
about Russia I don't know much about
Ukraine you're actually the only person
I kind of know who's in Ukraine
um Rey is a totally different different
killer fish he will know an immense
amount about Ukraine I do know about
Russia because I've been here for seven
years and I can give my own experiences
we'll definitely have you on again to
discuss life in Russia yeah that would
be awesome yeah yeah love you right yeah
and Ray what what final thought would
you like to leave us with
well I'd I'd like to have everyone who's
watching or listening know how to spell
pen quake
it's that tan again that you mentioned
initially and I'm going to spell it and
Susie you correct me if I'm wrong okay
p-a-n-q-u-a-k-e correct okay
now that's that's the outcome of an
immense effort
uh by people who know what they're doing
and I look I look very hopefully to that
as resource uh for something like The
Fifth Estate that Julian himself created
and enabled us to learn from
the thing I'll simply say is
one of my heroes uh was a Hungarian Jew
named ference
who became an Army lawyer and was one of
the last prosecutors
at noon back
he was asked you know for his advice as
to what we all should do
uh to try to be as tenacious as he was
in pursuing Justice and he said oh he
said is there just three things
you never give up
and you never give up
that's it folks I'm pleased to be with
folks who never give up
and on that note I think that we should
call it a stream I want to thank you all
my gentlemen all my guests rather
including John kiriaku uh Susie Dawson
Ray McGovern like I said before the
links to find them will be in the
description below I neglected to do that
before but by the time this this goes up
you'll see it and uh John if you're
listening like I said I'd love to have
you back on again I hope you sort out
your internet issues and Susie and Ray
of course you are always welcome
whenever you'd like to chat thanks so
much I hope you guys uh enjoyed the show
and I will catch you next time take it
easy
hi